# ELIANA SOLANO J

# INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS ADMINISTRATOR



# **PROFILE**

International business administrator with experience in customer service, logistics, export processes, import and customs. Person organized, determined, dynamic, with good interpersonal relationships and ability to do work team. High adaptability, patient and dedicated with willingness to serve.

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### **FOREIGN TRADE ASSISTANT**

INSUMMA BUSINESS GROUP - BUCARAMANGA APR 2018 - PRESENT

Be in contact with national and international suppliers, negotiate prices, find new suppliers and follow the purchasing process.

#### **ADMINISTRATOR**

LA GUERA MILAGROSA- CARTAGENA JAN 2016- DIC 2017

Responsible for managing a restaurant-bar, create events, retain customers and be the face of the Company, provide excellent service and serve VIP clients.

#### TRAINEE OF FOREIGN TRADE

AVM INDUSTRIES —BUCARAMANGA JAN 2015 – JUL 2015

Management of criteria of origin, processing of visas, creation of travel advances in SAP accounting software, unification of packing lists for export, quotation of spare parts for vehicles and equipment, tracking of imports and exports, currency trading, reconciliation of income and Expenses vs exchange of the account in compensation.

## **ADMINISTRATIVE ASSISTANT**

AIESEC INTERNATIONAL — SAO LUIS, BRAZIL JUN 2012 – NOV2012

Management of funds, creation of organization chart for the foundation, implementation and maintenance of database of benefactors, organization of documents, creation of projects to raise funds.

## **COSTUMER SERVICE**

STF GROUP — BUCARAMANGA DEC2012 — JAN 2015

Commercial advisor in charge of guiding potential consumers and promoting customer loyalty, be in contact with customers and offer them a personalized service

# **EDUCATION**

### INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS ADMINISTRATOR

UNIVERSIDAD PONTIFICIA BOLIVARIANA BUCARAMANGA ENE 2010—SEP 2015

#### **ACADEMIC BACHELOR**

COLEGIO TECNICO INDSUTRIAL JOSE ELIAS PUYANA FLORIDABLANCA ENE 2003 - DIC 2009

#### CONTACT

(+57) 6091388 (+57)300 6755834

☑ eliana.solano7@hotmail.com

☑ eliana.solano7@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/elianasj7

# **LANGUAGES**

SPANISH
ENGLISH
PORTUGUESE
FRENCH

# **COMPETENCES**

- Microsoft Office
- Critical thinking
- Customer Care
- ♦ Responsibility
- International logistic
- Creativity
- Assertive comunication
- ◆ Teamwork
- ♦ Leadership